{"test_questions": [[{"question": "A ripple counter's speed is limited by the propagation delay of:", "opta": "each flip-flop", "optb": "all flip-flops and gates", "optc": "the flip-flops only with gates", "optd": "only circuit gates", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "To operate correctly, starting a ring counter requires:", "opta": "clearing all the flip-flops", "optb": "presetting one flip-flop and clearing all the others", "optc": "clearing one flip-flop and presetting all the others", "optd": "presetting all the flip-flops", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "What type of register would shift a complete binary number in one bit at a time and shift all the stored bits out one bit at a time?", "opta": "PIPO", "optb": "SISO", "optc": "SIPO", "optd": "PISO", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Synchronous counters eliminate the delay problems encountered with asynchronous (ripple) counters because the:", "opta": "input clock pulses are applied only to the first and last stages", "optb": "input clock pulses are applied only to the last stage", "optc": "input clock pulses are not used to activate any of the counter stages", "optd": "input clock pulses are applied simultaneously to each stage", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "One of the major drawbacks to the use of asynchronous counters is that:", "opta": "low-frequency applications are limited because of internal  propagation delays", "optb": "high-frequency applications are limited because of internal propagation delays", "optc": "Asynchronous counters do not have major drawbacks and are suitable for use in high- and low-frequency counting applications.", "optd": "Asynchronous counters do not have propagation delays, which limits their use in high-frequency applications.", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Which type of device may be used to interface a parallel data format with external equipment's serial format?", "opta": "key matrix", "optb": "UART", "optc": "memory chip", "optd": "serial-in, parallel-out", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "When the output of a tri-state shift register is disabled, the output level is  placed in a:", "opta": "float state", "optb": "LOW state", "optc": "high impedance state", "optd": "float state and a high impedance state", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "A comparison between ring and johnson counters indicates that:", "opta": "a ring counter has fewer flip-flops but requires more decoding circuitry", "optb": "a ring counter has an inverted feedback path", "optc": "a johnson counter has more flip-flops but less decoding circuitry", "optd": "a johnson counter has an inverted feedback path", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "A sequence of equally spaced timing pulses may be easily generated by which type of counter circuit?", "opta": "shift register sequencer", "optb": "clock", "optc": "johnson", "optd": "binary", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "What is meant by parallel-loading the register?", "opta": "Shifting the data in all flip-flops simultaneously", "optb": "Loading data in two of the flip-flops", "optc": "Loading data in all four flip-flops at the same time", "optd": "Momentarily disabling the synchronous SET and RESET inputs", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "What is a shift register that will accept a parallel input and can shift data left or right called?", "opta": "tri-state", "optb": "end around", "optc": "bidirectional universal", "optd": "conversion", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "What happens to the parallel output word in an asynchronous binary down counter whenever a clock pulse occurs?", "opta": "The output word decreases by 1.", "optb": "The output word decreases by 2.", "optc": "The output word increases by 1.", "optd": "The output word increases by 2.", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Mod-6 and mod-12 counters are most commonly used in:", "opta": "frequency counters", "optb": "multiplexed displays", "optc": "digital clocks", "optd": "power consumption meters", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}]]}